A Guide to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company Records, 1836-1943
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Maps, 1836-1943., Extent: 196 maps.
  - Right of Way and Track Map. The Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company. Lexington Branch. June 30, 1916., Dimensions: each 24 x 18 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueline print.; Sheets: 12 sheets numbered 1 through 11, including a supplemental sheet, in 36 parts. (Othertype 755.812 S8 1916)
  - [Right of way map of] Lexington Branch [North River, Rockbridge County]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 24 x 36 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 19 sheets, including 2 supplemental sheets. (Othertype 755.812 S8 n.d.)
  - Map No. I [shows James River and canal in vicinity of Buchanon and Pattonsburg (Botetourt County)]. n.d.., Dimensions: 27 x 20 in. and 27 x 18 in.; Scale: 1000 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.814 C2 n.d.)
  - Map No. II [shows James River and canal in Botetourt County, from Catawba Creek to Rich Patch Mountain]. n.d.., Dimensions: 27 x 19 in. and 27 x 16 in.; Scale: 1000 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.814 C2 n.d. (1))
  - Map No. III [shows James River and canal in the vicinity of Wood's Island (Botetourt County)]. n.d.., Dimensions: 27 x 18.5 in.; Scale: 1000 ft. to l in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.814 C2 n.d. (2))
  - Jackson. [Botetourt County] R. and A. R. R. 1883., Dimensions: 27 x 15, 27 x 18.5, and 27 x 17 in.; Scale: 50 ft to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 755.814 R15 1883)
  - Map of L. C. Watson's Land [Bath County]. March 1885., Dimensions: 12.5 x 33 in.; Scale: 300 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plat on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.924 S8 1885)
  - [Map of right of way through Bath County from Rockbridge County line to Alleghany County line.] Centre line from Maj. Temple's survey. n.d.., Dimensions: each 23 x 36 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 7. (Othertype 755.924 S8 n.d.)
  - Map No. IV [shows Jackson River and canal in vicinity of Clifton Forge (Alleghany County)]. n.d.., Dimensions: 27 x 19 in. and 27 x 18 in.; Scale: 1000 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.926 C2 n.d.)
  - "C[har1es] B. Fisk's Line. Covington, Va., and West of Alleghany Tunnel." [Surveys of proposed routes of railroad near Dunlap's Creek (Alleghany County)]. 1853?., Dimensions: each 22 x 30 in.; Scale: 400 ft. [to 1 in.].; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 9 manuscript sheets in 3 sets: numbered 1-6 (3-4 missing), a single sheet, and numbered 1-4. (Othertype 755.926 R15 1853?)
  - [Map sheets numbered 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, and 12, Alleghany County, showing right of way for Covington and Ohio Railroad]. 1858-1859., Dimensions: Sheet 7, 17-1/2 x 22 in. Sheets 8-12, 23 x 28 in.; Scale: 400 ft. to 1 in., except for sheet number 9 (100 ft. to 1 in.).; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 6. (Othertype 755.926 S8 1858-1859)
  - Land of John Mallow [Alleghany County], condemned for the Virginia Central Railroad Company. Filed Sept. 16, 1861. Copied from original plat Jan. 17, 1877. 1861-1877., Dimensions: 7 x 23.5 in.; Scale: 200 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.926 S8 1861-1877)
  - Right of Way near Alleghany Station [Alleghany County], Virginia. December 1886., Dimensions: in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in. in.; Media: Manuscript plat on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.926 S8 1886)
  - Alleghany Co. [Map of right of way from Bath County line to Alleghany Tunnel]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 21 x 35 in.; Scale: 100 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript map. Colored.; Sheets: 31. (Othertype 755.926 S8 n.d.)
  - Land purchased from E. Nicely at Longdale Station [Alleghany County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 14.5 x 15 in.; Scale: [20 ft. to 1 in.].; Media: Manuscript plat on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.926 S8 n.d. (1))
  - [Plat of right of way through land of William H. Haynes's estate, Alleghany County]. n.d.., Dimensions: each 10.5 x 25 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plat on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.926 S8 (2))
  - [Plat of Iron Mountain Depot at Mallow, Alleghany County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 7 x 24.5 in.; Scale: [200 ft. to 1 in.].; Media: Manuscript plat on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.926 S8 (3))
  - Map fragments. 1852-1885., Media: Fragments of blueprint and manuscript maps.; Sheets: 4.
- Series II: Plans, 1848-1927., Extent: 67 plans.
  The plans are for dams, designs for a pile hammer, sections through canals and water sheet pits, and profiles of riverbeds. There are also plans for fish ladders, canal lock gates and their machinery, gauging platforms, a lighter, and a bridge over the Manchester Canal.
  - [Unidentified railroad yard?] Plans in 3 differing scales. K.E. Hilgard, Prin. Asst. Eng., Janu. 30, 1890; Feb. 1890; n.d.., Dimensions: 11 x 34, 20 x 32, 9 x 40 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Three manuscript plans on linen paper.; Sheets: 3. (Othertype 750 Z3 1890, n.d.)
  - Sketch Showing Dimensions of 250 lb. Pile Hammer. Jan. 29th, 1891., Dimensions: 8.75 x 9.75 in.; Scale: 6 in. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754 Z1 1891)
  - Frame for 250 lb. Pile Hammer. Jan. 31st, 1891., Dimensions: 14.5 x 18 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript preliminary plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754 Z2 1891)
  - Frame for 250 lb. Pile Hammer. Jan. 31st, 1891., Dimensions: 14.5 x 18 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript tracing on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754 Z2 1891 (1))
  - General Plan of Dam for Elk River Shoals [Kanawha County, West Virginia]. Plan of Water-Way. E[daard] Lorraine. n.d.., Dimensions: 20 x 29.5 in.; Scale: 4 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 754.37 Z1 n.d.)
  - [Plans of canal lock gates, frames, etc.]. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: Scales differ.; Media: Manuscript plans. (Othertype 755 Z12 n.d.)
  - Sheet No. 4 to General Plan (dated the 24th of March 1852) of Combined Locks for the 3rd Division J. R. & K. Co. June 30th, 1852., Dimensions: 18 x 24 in.; Scale: 4 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z13 1852)
  - [Pencil sketches of sections through canal lock]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan. (Othertype 755 Z14 n.d.)
  - [Plan of valves (for canal lock?)]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 3/4 in.; Media: Manuscript drawing.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z15 n.d.)
  - Arrangement of Planking, etc., for sides of Composite Locks. May 16, 1850., Dimensions: 13.5 x 19 in.; Scale: 2 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan. (Othertype 755 Z16 n.d.)
  - Feeding Sluices. Locks No. 6 & 7. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 4 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z17 n.d.)
  - [Section through part of canal lock]. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z18 n.d.)
  - Lock Gate. n.d.., Dimensions: 19.5 x 27.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plans and sections. Colored.; Sheets:. (Othertype 755 Z19 n.d.)
  - Mitre Sills and Quoins. Lock No. 9. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z20 n.d.)
  - Gate and Mitre Sill Plan. Lock 18. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 21 in.; Scale: Scales differ.; Media: Manuscript plans. (Othertype 755 Z21 n.d.)
  - [Plan of water gate for canal Lock]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z22 n.d.)
  - [Section of dam]. n.d.., Dimensions: 14 x 14.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z23 n.d.)
  - Great Falls Fishway [Potomac River]. n.d.., Dimensions: 19 x 25 in.; Scale: Scales differ.; Media: Printed plans and sections. (Othertype 755 Z24 n.d.)
  - Great Falls Fishway [Potomac River]. Location Plan of First Section. C. E. Gorham, C. E. n.d.., Dimensions: 24 x 19 in.; Scale: 7 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Printed plans. (Othertype 755 Z25 n.d.)
  - Great Falls Fishway [Potomac River]. Location Plan of Second Section. n.d.., Dimensions: 23 x 16 in.; Scale: 7.5 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Printed plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z26 n.d.)
  - Plan of Clamps for Guard Locks. Applicable also to Lift Locks. Dec. 24, 1849., Dimensions: each 12 x 18 in.; Scale: 5 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755 Z27 1849)
  - Plan of Clamps for Guard Locks. Applicable also to Lift Locks. Dec. 24, 1849. Traced by E. Thomas, Oct. 6, 1927. Oct. 6, 1927., Dimensions: 12 x 36 in.; Scale: 5 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755 Z28 1849 1927)
  - Plan of Clamps for Guard Locks. Applicable also to Lift Locks. Dec. 24, 1849. Traced by E. Thomas, Oct. 6, 1927. Dec. 24, 1849., Dimensions: 12 x 36 in.; Scale: 5 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint plan.; Sheets: 5 copies, 1 each. (Othertype 755 Z29 1849 1927 (1) copies 1-5)
  - Waste Gates at Haxall [Henrico County], showing Repairs and Changes. November 1892., Dimensions: each 22 x 23 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper, in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.43 Z1 1892)
  - Vertical Section and Plan of Locks from Tenth to Thirteenth Street [Richmond]. n.d.., Dimensions: 23.5 x 58 in.; Scale: 20 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan backed with blueprint paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z22 n.d.)
  - Lighter for Steam Dredge. F. B. Isaacs. July 1891., Dimensions: 19 x 26 in. and 19 x 21 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plans, in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 Z23 1891)
  - General plan of gauging platform at 5th St., below Tredegar Iron Works. Richmond, Va. Dec. 4, 1890., Dimensions: l7 x 22 in.; Scale: 1 ft to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890)
  - Sections & elevations corresponding to 5th St. Plan [of gauging platform] Below Tredegar Iron Works. Richmond, Va. Dec. 4, 1890., Dimensions: 9 x 18.5 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890 (1))
  - General Plan Showing the Location of Gauging Platform at the Richmond Paper Mills, Richmond, Va. Nov. 18, 1890., Dimensions: 26.5 x 20.5 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890 (2))
  - General plan of gauging platform near old city pump house. Richmond, Va. [1890?]., Dimensions: each 18 x 18 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890?)
  - Elevation of Bridge & Gauging Platform near 2nd St. Shops. Above Tredegar Iron Works. Richmond, Va. [1890?]., Dimensions: each 20 x 18 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890? (1))
  - [Plans of] gauging platform at 12th St. Arch (Gallego tail race), Richmond, Va. [1890?]., Dimensions: 18.5 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale varies.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z24 1890? (2))
  - Section of Gates to Tredegar, Gallego, and Paper Mill. Eng's Office R. & A. R. R. October 25th, l88l. Measurements made June 19, 1881. 1881., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript sections. (Othertype 755.44 Z25 1881 copies 1 & 2)
  - [Sections through wheel pits, etc., near Tredegar Iron. Works, Richmond]. [l88l?]., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript sections. (Othertype 755.44 Z25 1881?)
  - [Sections through canal near Tredegar Iron Works, Richmond. l88l?] Changed Oct. 26,1882. 1881, 1882., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript sections. (Othertype 755.44 Z25 [1881?] 1882)
  - Cross Section of Basin in front of Gallego Mills, Richmond, Va. July 30, 1891., Dimensions: 11 x 17 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript section.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z25 1891)
  - Gallego Mill, Turbine Installations. R. D. Trimble & Co., Consulting Engineers, Richmond, Va. Aug. 31, 1926., Dimensions: each 18 x 22 in.; Scale: 8 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint plans.; Sheets: 4. (Othertype 755.44 Z26 1926 copies 1-4)
  - Situation plan showing forebay and wheel pits at Gallego Mills. Richmond, Va. May 30, 1923., Dimensions: 19 x 24.5 in.; Scale: 4 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Blueprint plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.44 Z27 1923)
  - Maiden's Adventure Fishway [Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 24 x 31 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/4 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d.)
  - Richmond and Alleghany R. R. Office of Engineer of Water Power. Plan of Fishway at Maiden's Adventure Dam [Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 27 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/8 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (1))
  - Richmond and Alleghany R. R. Office of Engineer of Water Power. Plan of Fishway at Maiden's Adventure Dam [Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 24 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/8 in.; Media: Blueprint plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (2))
  - [Plan of fishway at Maiden's Adventure Dam, Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 23 x 12 in. and 12 x 13 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/4 in.; Media: Manuscript plan in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (3))
  - Maiden's Adventure Fishway [Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 13 x 22 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/8 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (4))
  - Maiden's Adventure Fishway [Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 13 x 23 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/8 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (5))
  - [Maiden's Adventure Fishway, Goochland County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 14 x 24 in.; Scale: [1 ft. to 1/8 in].; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.442 Z3 n.d. (6))
  - [Plan and elevation of Scott's mill, Fluvanna Co., Va.]. n.d.., Dimensions: 26.5 x 38 in.; Scale: 1/4 in. to 1 ft.; Media: Manuscript drawing. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.454 Z1 n.d.)
  - Plan for Water gate at Masons Mill, Scottsville [Albemarle County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 12.5 x 15.5 in.; Scale: 2 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.47 Z3 1848?)
  - Gates for the River Lock at Judith Falls Dam [Amherst County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 20 x 27 in.; Scale: 4 ft. to 1 in. Scales differ.; Media: Manuscript plan. Colored,including details of gates.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.483 Z1 n.d.)
  - Plan for Repairing, strengthening, and lengthening Judith Dam [Amherst County] by E. Lorraine. n.d.., Dimensions: each 18 x 26 in. Copy 2, each 18-1/2 x 14 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan, in 2 parts. Copy 2, Neg. photostats in 4 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.483 Z2 n.d. Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - Front View of Judith Dam [Amherst County] Shewing the Breach. n.d.., Dimensions: each l8 x 23 in. Copy 2, each 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 10 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan, in 2 parts. Copy 2, Neg. photostat in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.483 Z2 n.d. (1) Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - Bridge over Manchester Canal in Hull Street. F. B. Isaacs. April 28, 1891., Dimensions: each 14 x 18 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/4 in.; Media: Manuscript plan in 2 parts.; Sheets: 2. (Othertype 755.57 Z2 1891)
  - Sheet piling of waste-way of water-works Canal. Lynchburg, Va. January 30, 1891., Dimensions: 18 x 31 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.59 Z1 1891)
  - Blackwater Creek Aqueduct at Lynchburg, Va. Wrought Iron Details. F. B. Isaacs, Desgr. September 1893., Dimensions: 18 x 13 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 3 in.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.59 Z2 1893)
  - New Lynchburg Freight Depot. n.d.., Dimensions: 10.5 x 37.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan on linen paper.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.59 Z3 n.d.)
  - [Profiles and plans]. Old Canal from Agner's Dam to Mill [Rockbridge County]. July 1892., Dimensions: 14 x 17 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript profiles and plans.; Sheets: 6. (Othertype 755.812 Z1 1892 (1))
  - [Plan of wheels and wheel pits, Agner's Mill, Rockbridge County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 12 x 25.5 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/8 in.; Media: Manuscript map.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.812 Z2 n.d.)
  - Blue Ridge Dam [Rockbridge County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 15 x 19.5 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 1/2 in.; Media: Manuscript plan. Colored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.812 Z3 n.d.)
  - Cabell Dam [Botetourt County]. Plan proposed by A. T. Fort. Not adopted. n.d.., Dimensions: 18.5 x 23 in. Copy 2, 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 2 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan (elevation) of dam. Copy 2, Neg. photostat.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z1 n.d. Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - Plan of Foundation Walls. Guard Lock No. 1. Cabell Dam [Botetourt County]. 5th March 1856., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: 8 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z2 1856)
  - Cabell's Dam [Botetourt County]. River Lock. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: funuscrfpt plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z3 n.d.)
  - River Lock Gates at Cabell Dam [Botetourt County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in. Copy 2, 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript p1an. Copy 2, Neg. photostat.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z4 n.d. Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - North Abutment of Cabe11 Dam [Botetourt County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 22 in. Copy 2, 18 x 22 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript plan. Coiored.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z5 n.d. Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - Section of Gwynn Dam [Botetourt County]. n.d.., Dimensions: 11 x l7 in.; Scale: 1 ft. to 2 squares.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.816 Z6 n.d.)
  - River Lock at Gwynn Dam. Sept. 22nd, 1854., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: 6 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan. Copy 2, Neg. photostat.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z7 1854 Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - River Lock at Gwynn Dam. n.d.., Dimensions: 17 x 23 in.; Scale: 6 ft. to 1 in.; Media: Manuscript plan.; Sheets: 1. (Othertype 755.814 Z8 n.d. Copy 1 Copy 2)
  - Plan (incomplete). Fragment of unidentified plan. n.d.., Sheets: 1.
- Series III: Charts, 1870-1927., Extent: 25 charts and graphs.
  The charts primarily show the relative depth of the canal or river bottom over a period of time. Other charts pertain to the use of water power at Richmond.
  - Records of Freshets at Richmond: Report of Committee to Board of Aldermen, Oct. 11, 1886 (4 pp.), and neg. photostat of same. Covers 1870-1886. Four manuscript charts, 1893-1896. Two letters, Oct. and Nov. 1896, concerning records of freshets at Richmond, accompanies by two pages of statistics., Dimensions: Vary; Media: Manuscripts and negative photostats.
  - Average Gauge Observations at Three Mile Lock. Gauge below Gates. January 2, 1881-June 30, 1884., Dimensions: each 8.5 x 18 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript charts.; Sheets: 5.
  - Canal Gaugings. June 23-Sep. 17th, 1881., Dimensions: each 15.5 x 29 in., except part 1, 15.5 x 22.5 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript chart of relative depth and shape of canal bottom in the Henrico County-Richmond City vicinity, in 8 parts; Sheets: 8.
  - Gauges on Richmond Level from Sept. 20th to Dec. 31st, 1881. Sept. 20th to Dec. 31st, 1881., Dimensions: each 11.5 x 29 in., except parts 1 and 2, 11.5 x 19 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript chart of relative depth and shape of canal bottom in the Henrico County-Richmond City vicinity, in 8 parts; Sheets: 8.
  - Gauges Richmond Level. Jan. 2nd-Mar. 31st, 1882., Dimensions: each 11.5 x 29 in., except parts 6 and 7, 11.5 x 19 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript chart of relative depth and shape of canal bottom in the Henrico County-Richmond City vicinity, in 7 parts; Sheets: 7.
  - Gauges, Richmond Level. July 1-September 30, 1882., Dimensions: each 10.5 x 29.5 in., except part 7, 10.5 x 24 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript chart of relative depth and shape of canal bottom in the Henric-County Richmond City vicinity, in 7 parts; Sheets: 7.
  - Current Meter Rating. McRae's Lock. Corrected Revolutions. Aug. 1882., Dimensions: 12.5 x 22 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript graph.; Sheets: 1.
  - Calculations and estimates of work done on Lynchburg Dam prior to 30 Sept. 1882. Charts listing types and quantities of material used. prior to 30 Sept. 1882., Dimensions: each 18 x 23 in.; Scale:; Media: One packet of calculations and 16 manuscript charts; Sheets: 16.
  - Results of Current Hetre Observations. Richmond Level. Rating of October 1891. October 1891., Dimensions: 19 x 33 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript chart.; Sheets: 1.
  - [Chart showing lessees using water power at Richmond, amounts claimed by each, information concerning leases, and data concerning water flow, with a summary chart concerning cubic feet per second used]. 1891-1912., Dimensions: each 17 x 30 in. Small chart 9.5 x 30 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Two manuscript charts and two blueprint copies of larger chart.; Sheets: 4.
  - Cross-sections taken as shewn on Map (of June 25th, 1892) showing portion of Canal near Burnt Mill Trestle. [1892?]., Dimensions: 15.5 x 16 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript profile.; Sheets: 1.
  - Graphic comparison of gauge height and quantity at Gallego Mills, Richmond Paper Hill, Albemarle Paper Mill, and Tredegar Company. Feb.-April 1912., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Scale: Scale not given.; Media: Manuscript graph.; Sheets: 1.
  - Current meter observations on Richmond level of canal. Gaugings taken April 27, 1912, and earlier. By F. B. Isaacs. April 27, 1912., Dimensions: 14.5 x 26 in.; Media: Manuscript chart.; Sheets: 1.
  - Current meter observations on Richmond level of canal. Gaugings taken April 27, 1912, and earlier. By F. B. Isaacs. Traced by E. Thomas, Real Estate Dept., C. & O. Ry., Sept. 27, 1927, from F. B. Isaacs report. Sept. 27, 1927., Dimensions: 14.5 x 26 in.; Media: Manuscript chart.; Sheets: 1.
  - Hydrograph of Gage Read~ngs and Gate Openings. C. and O. Canal. Sept. 23 to 25, 1926., Dimensions: 22 x 35 in.; Media: Three blueprint charts.; Sheets: 3.
  - Discharge measurements in C. & O. Canal. September 1926., Dimensions: 11 x 8.5 in.; Media: Blueprint charts, in 4 sets: 3 contain pages 1-5, 8, 9, 11. One contains only pages 8, 9, 11.
  - [Gauges of James River. July 8-18. Year and place not given]. n.d.., Dimensions: 16.5 x 46.5 in.; Media: Manuscript chart.; Sheets: 1.
  - Estimates and cost of Lynchburg Dam [a series of sections on graph paper]. n.d.., Dimensions: 18 x 23 in.; Media: Manuscript graph.; Sheets: 1.
- Series IV: Records, 1886-1898., Extent: 16 items.
  The records consist of letters and proposals concerning construction or alterations affecting the property of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company. Most of these manuscripts relate to the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company maps.
  - Letter, W.C. Wickham, Richmond, Virginia, to William A. Quarrier, Charleston, West Virginia, 30 April 1886., 3 items (Folder a)
    Proposal concerning transfer track near Charleston [see 754.37/S8/1886].
  - Proposal, Reuben Shirreffs, Richmond, Virginia [to Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, Richmond, Virginia], 18 July 1892., 2 items (Folder b)
    Calculations for development and improvement of water power at Richmond [see 755.44/H9/1892].
  - Proposal, Reuben Shirreffs, Richmond, Virginia, to Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, Old Dominion Nail Works Company, The Haxall Crenshaw Company, et. al., 6 December 1892., 3 items (Folder c)